Woobin Im

Korean name: 임우빈 Ph.D. student at

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

SGVR Lab.

email: <u>iwbn@kaist.ac.kr</u>

github: https://github.com/iwbn website: https://github.com/iwbn

About Me

I'm a Ph.D. student at KAIST, South Korea. My research is mainly focused on solving **computer vision** problems using **machine learning**. Specifically, my research has been focusing on computer vision problems where a prior in data needs to be modeled properly, e.g., unsupervised learning. Here's a brief list of my topics of interest:

- **Optical flow estimation:** it is a fundamental feature for video recognition. I have been mainly focusing on the lack of datasets with ground-truth optical flow, e.g., unsupervised / semi-supervised learning.
- Un/semi-supervised learning: learning with unlabeled examples is not avoidable in some applications: unsupervised optical flow estimation, single-sample per person (SSPP) face recognition, etc.
- Video recognition: recognizing video contents by machine learning.
- Face recognition: recognizing identity, age, and other attributes with machine-learning.

Not only on the topics mentioned above, I'm knowledgeable about 3D vision and NLP. I have been implemented my code using Python, C++ with OpenCV, Tensorflow (1 and 2), and Pytorch, while participating in many vision-related projects: face recognition, 3D teleportation, and multi-view line matching.

Education

- KAIST, Ph.D., Computer Science, 2018-current
 - Advisor: Professor Sung-Eui Yoon
- KAIST, M.S., Computer Science, 2016-2018
 - Advisor: Professor Hyun Seung Yang
- Yonsei University, B.S., Computer Science, 2012-2016

Publications

• Semi-Supervised Learning of Optical Flow by Flow Supervisor Woobin Im, Sebin Lee, and Sung-Eui Yoon

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022

[web] [arxiv] [github]

• In-N-Out: Towards Good Initialization for Inpainting and Outpainting

<u>Changho Jo</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC)*, 2021 [web] [arxiv] [github]

• Self-Supervised Visual Odometry via Frame Interpolation

<u>Sebin Lee</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2021 [paper]

• Unsupervised Learning of Optical Flow with Deep Feature Similarity

Woobin Im, <u>Tae-Kyun Kim</u>, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020 [web] [paper] [github]

• Combined Center Dispersion Loss Function for Deep Facial Expression Recognition

<u>Abhilasha Nanda</u>, **Woobin Im**, <u>Key-Sun Choi</u>, and <u>Hyun Seung Yang Pattern Recognition Letters</u>, 2020 [paper]

• Two-stream Spatiotemporal Feature for Video QA Task

<u>Chiwan Song</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> <u>https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.05006</u>, 2019 [arxiv]

Acoustic Material Estimation with Convolutional Neural Network

Doheon Lee, <u>Inkyu An</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2019 [paper]

• An Application of Convolutional-LSTM Network and Video QA

<u>Chiwan Song</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *Korea Computer Congress (KCC)*, 2018 [paper]

• Scale-Varying Triplet Ranking with Classification Loss for Facial Age Estimation

Woobin Im, <u>Sungeun Hong</u>, <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u>, and <u>Hyun S. Yang</u> *Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV)*, 2018 [web] [paper] [github]

• CBVMR: Content-Based Video-Music Retrieval Using Soft Intra-Modal Structure Constraint

<u>Sungeun Hong</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Hyun S. Yang</u>

Proceedings of the ACM international conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR), 2018

[paper] [video]

• D3: Recognizing dynamic scenes with deep dual descriptor based on key frames and key segments

<u>Sungeun Hong, Jongbin Ryu</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Hyun S. Yang Neurocomputing</u>, 2018
[paper]

• SSPP-DAN: Deep Domain Adaptation Network for Face Recognition with Single Sample Per Person

<u>Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, Jongbin Ryu,</u> and <u>Hyun S. Yang</u> *International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP'17), IEEE*, 2017 **Oral** [paper]

- Convolutional Texture Networks based on Histogram Pooling Jongbin Ryu, Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, and Hyun S. Yang
- Image-text multi-modal representation learning by adversarial backpropagation <u>Gwangbeen Park</u> and Woobin Im arXiv preprint arXiv:1612.08354, 2016
- Deep CNN-based Person Identification using Facial and Clothing Features Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, Junwoo Park, and Hyun S. Yang Jun 2016, Summer General Conference '16, IEEK, 2016

Patents

- Using Triplet-based Loss for Training Ordinal Classification Deep Models [detail]
- Partial Face Based Person Identification Across Poses [detail]

Projects

- Rendering for teleportaion in AR devices
 - Mar 2018 Dec 2020, funded by National Research Foundation (NRF)
- Lab website renovation, Dec 2019 (sgvr.kaist.ac.kr)
- Age, gender, and expression recognition using face images
 - o Dec 2016 Feb 2018, funded by Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology
- Multi-view Face Recognition based on Deep Learning
 - May 2016 May 2017, funded by Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)

Experiences

- Teaching Assistants
 - GSAG-KAIST Research and Education Program, 1/2019-2/2019
 - o CS206: Data Structure (Spring 2019), 3/2019-6/2019
 - o CS688: Web-Scale Image Retrieval (Fall 2018), 9/2018-12/2018
 - CS101: Introduction to Programming, 9/2016-12/2017, 9/2018-12/2018
- Undergraduate Research Assistant
 - o DB Lab, Yonsei University, 1/2014-2/2014